A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, President, Karen Davis papers, SG 2 FA1127
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, President, Karen Davis papers, SG 2
1968-2012
1995-2012
Rockefeller Archive Center
Davis, Karen
Commonwealth Fund
FA1127
67.94 Cubic Feet
Scope and Contents
This collection includes copies of Karen Davis' testimonies, speeches, presentations, and publications. Drafts, related research material, and correspondence are also present throughout the collection. Davis' papers also include records of internal and external meetings, related conferences and workshops, and Commonwealth Fund program files and reviews.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into five series:
1. Congressional Testimony files, 1973-2008
2. Publications, 1972-2009
3. Correspondence
4. Speeches and Presentations
5. Meetings and Program Files
Separated Materials
Special format items have been separated from the body of the collection and assigned a unique separation number, as noted. Requests to access open special formats should reference the unique separation number.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund archive was donated to RAC in 1985. Accretions to the collection continue on an ongoing basis. This material was transferred to the Archive Center as multiple accessions, spanning 2002-2014. Accessions include: 2002:030, 2002:031, 2002:051, 2002:052, 2007:055, 2008:065, 2012:070, 2013:002, 2013:007, 2013:008, 2014:042
Biographical / Historical
Karen E. Davis served as president of the Commonwealth Fund from 1995-2012. She spent a large part of her career at the Johns Hopkins School of Public Health as a professor of economics, and later as chairman of the Department of Health Policy and Management. Karen Davis has since been involved in the Geisinger Health System, IOM governing Council and various IOM Committees, AcademyHealth, the Kaiser Commission on Medicaid and the Uninsured, the Agency for Healthcare Quality and Research (AHRQ) National Advisory Committee, and has served on the Panel of Health Advisors for the Congressional Budget Office.
Medicare; Medical care -- United States; Insurance, Health -- United States -- Government policy; Medical care, Cost of--United States
- Congressional Testimony records, 1973-2008; 1; 4.18 Cubic Feet 11 letter document boxes
  - T0 - Hospital Costs, 1973-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - T1 - National Health Insurance and Health Care, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - T3 - Rural Health Care - Problems and Prospects, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - T6 - "Is the Health Care Cost Problem Solved?", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - T10 - "Tax Incentives and Health Care Costs", 1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - T11 - Statement by Karen Davis before the Subcommittee on Health and the Environment Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, 1980 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - T12 - "Medicaid and Health Care of the Poor," Washington, D.C., 1981 July 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - T13 - "Recent Trends in Hospital Costs: Failure of the Voluntary Effort", 1981 December 15 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - T14 - "Access to Health Care Services for the Poor", 1982 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - T15 - "Reducing the Federal Deficit by Cutting Medicare and Medicaid: Impact on the Poor, Disabled, and Elderly", 1983 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - T16 - "Financing Medicare: A New Approach", 1983 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - T17 - "The Cost of Health Care for Families", 1983 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - T18 - "Supporting a Family: Providing the Basics", 1983 July 18 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - T19 - The Future of Medicare, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - T20 - "The Cost of Health Care for the Elderly", 1984 January 26 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - T21 - "Assuring a Sound and Adequate Medicare Program", 1984 February 22 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - T22 - "Catastrophic Coverage Under Medicare", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - T23 - Work Session on Cross National Data, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - T24 - House Committee on Aging Testimony, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - T25 - "Medicare: Medigap for the Poor and Elderly", 1986 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - T26 - Physician Bills and Medicare Beneficiaries, 1986 June 10 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - T27 - Joint Economic Committee Testimony - Child Health Research Funding, 1986 August 4 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - T28 - Senate Finance Committee, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - T31 - Family Welfare Reform Act, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - T32 - Employment and Health Insurance Testimony, 1987 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - T33 - "Improving Access to Primary Care and Catastrophic Health Care for Children", 1987 October 2 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - T34 - Senate/Labor - The Economic Impact of Employer Minimum Health Insurance Coverage, 1987 November 4 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - T35 - "Improving Access to Health Care and Assuring Catastrophic Protection for Children, 1987 October 2 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Preventitive Health Care for the Elderly, Miami, Florida, 1988 January 6 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - T36 - Out-of-Pocket Health Care Costs - House Conferees, 1988 February 25 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - T37 - House of Delegates Testimony - Physician Bills and Medicare Assignment - Baltimore, Maryland, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - T38 - Minimum Health Benefits for All Workers, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - T39 - Physician Payment Review Commission: Fiscal Year 1989 Budget Review, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - T40 - The Future of Health Care in America, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 34-36)
  - T41 - "Closing the Gaps in Health Insurance Coverage", 1988 January-September (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - T42 - "Toward Better Health Insurance Coverage", 1988 September 22 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - T43 - "Improving the Quality of Life Among Elderly Women Living Alone", 1988 September 27 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - T44 - "Medicare Part B Expenditures: Out of Control?", 1989 March 3 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - T45 - Statement of the Physician Payment Review Commission before the Subcommittee on Health Committee on Ways and Means, 1989 April 25 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - T46 - Trends in Medicare Expenditures, Ways and Means Retreat, 1989 April 28-30 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - T47 - "A Policy Proposal to Improve the United States Health Care System", 1989 September 11 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - T48 - Deficit Reduction Caucus, 1989 April 18 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - T49 - "Universal Health Insurance," Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care, 1989 July 20 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - T50 - "Overview of the United States' Health Care System", 1989 September 18 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - T51 - "Problems with Health Insurance Coverage", 1990 January 22 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - T52 - Statement of the Physician Payment Review Commissio on its Fiscal Year 1991 Budget Request, 1990 April 3 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - T53 - "Health Insurance for All Americans: the Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care Plan", 1990 April 6 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - T54 - "Uninsured Older Adults: The Need for a Medicare Buy-In Option," Ways and Means Committee, 1990 June 12 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - T55 - Pepper Commission Report, 1990 June 14 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - T56 - Statement of the Physician Payment Review Commission before the Subcommittee on Medicare and Long Term Care Committee on Finance, 1990 May 18 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - T57 - "Why Are Americans Uninsured?", 1991 April 19-21 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - T58 - "Public Approaches to Universal Coverage", 1991 April 19-21 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - T59 - "National Health Insurance: Issues and Options", 1991 April 23 (Box 8, Folder 55-56)
  - T60 - National Health Insurance Briefing, Ways and Means, 1991 February 21 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - T61 - "Medicaid for Women and Children: An Investment in Healthy Children", 1991 June 20 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - T62 - "Lessons of Medicare and Medicaid for National Health Insurance", 1991 June 27 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - T63 - "The Health and Economic Implications of Health America: Affordable Health Care for all Americans", 1991 June 24 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - T64 - Physician Payment Review Commission on Health Care Cost Containment, 1991 October 31 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - T65 - Charts for House Democratic Caucus Retreat, Piney Point, MD, 1992 January 30-31 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - T66 - "Comprehensive Health Care Reform", 1992 May 6 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - T67 - "Controlling Health Care Expenditures: Limits and Managed Competition", 1992 December 16 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - T68 - "A Single Payer Approach to Health Care Reform", 1993 January 9 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - T69 - "Health Insurance Coverage and Health Care Reform Options", 1993 January 25 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - T70 - "Health Care Reform: Problems, Issues, and Options" presented to Hillary Rodham Clinton, 1993 February 12 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - T71 - "Health Care Reform: Problems, Issues, and Options" presented to Ways and Means, 1993 February 12 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - T72 - "Rising Health Care Costs: Causes and Cures" presented to the Finance Committee, 1993 October 6 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - T73 - "President's Health Care Reform Plan: Implications for Urban America" Ways and Means, 1993 November 4 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - T74 - "Women's Health and Health Care Reform", 1994 January 26 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - T75 - "Medicare Turns Thirty" Finance Committee, 1995 February 28 (Box 10, Folder 72)
  - T76 - "Medicare Solvency and Financial Security for Beneficiaries", 1995 May 3 (Box 10, Folder 73)
  - T77 - "Medicare Restructuring and Financial Security for Beneficiaries", 1995 August 3 (Box 10, Folder 74)
  - T78 - "Medicare Budgetary Savings: Implications for Beneficiaries", 1995 September 22 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - T79 - "Medicaid: The Health Care Safety Net for the Nation's Poor", 1996 June 19 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - T80 - "Medicare Reform: Assuring Health and Economic Security for Beneficiaries", 1997 January 23 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - T81 - "Medicare Budget Savings: Are We On the Right Course for the Long-Term?", 1997 February 13 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - T82 - "Medicare: Options for the Long Term", 1997 March 6 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - T83 - "Managed Care, Choice, and Patient Satisfaction", 1997 June 25 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - T85 - "Shaping the Future of Medicare", 1998 April 21 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - T86 - "Assuring Quality, Information, and Choice in Managed Care", 1997 October 28 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - T87 - "Medicare's Cost-Sharing: Implications for Beneficiaries", 2001 May 9 (Box 11, Folder 83)
  - T88 - "A Time for Change: The Hidden Costs of a Fragmented Health Insurance System" presented to the Special Committee on Aging, 2003 March 10 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - T89 - "American Health Care: Why So Costly?", 2003 June 11 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - T90 - "Making Health Care Affordable for All Americans", 2004 January 28 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - T91 - "Hospital Pricing Behavior and Patient Financial Risk", 2004 June 22 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - T93 - "Learning form High Performance Health Systems around the Globe," Senate HELP Hearing, 2007 January 1 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - "Rethinking the GDP as Measurement of National Strength," Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Hearing, 2008 March 12 (Box 11, Folder 89)
- Publications, 1971-2009; 2; 15.76 Cubic Feet 41 letter document box and 1 half-box
  - 4 - "Economic Theories of Behavior in Non-Profit, Private Hospitals", undated (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - 5 - "The Substitution of Hospital Outpatient Care for Inpatient Care," The Review of Economics and Statistics, 1972 May (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - 9 - "Theories of Hospital Inflation: Some Empirical Evidence," Journal of Human Resources, undated (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - 12 - "The Role of Technology, Demand and Labor Markets in the Determination of Hospital Costs," The Economics of Health and Medical Care, undated (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - 13 - "Chapter 4: Financing Medical Care: Implications for Access to Primary Care," Primary Care: Where Medicine Fails, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - 15 - "Economics of Mental Health," Mental Health: The Public Health Challenge, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - 16 - "Medicare and the Utilization of Health Care Services by the Elderly," The Journal of Human Resources, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - 17 - "Equal Treatment and Unequal Benefits: The Medicare Program," MMFQ, Health and Society, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - 19 - "The Impact of Inflation and Unemployment on Health Care of Low-Income Families", 1976 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - 21 -"Rural Health Care in the South," Preliminary Summary Report, 1975 October (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - 22 - "Achievements and Problems of Medicaid", 1976 August (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - 23 - "A Decade of Policy Developments in Providing Health Care for Low-Income Families", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - 25 - "New Developments in the Market for Rural Health Care," Research in Health Economics, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - 26 - "Reagan Administration Health Policy," Journal of Public Health Policy, 1981 December (Box 12, Folder 103)
  - 27 - "Primary Care for the Medically Underserved: Public and Private Funding", 1981 (Box 12, Folder 104)
  - 28 - "Access to Health Care for the Poor: Does the Gap Remain?," American Review of Public Health, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 105)
  - 29 - "Implications of an Expanding Supply of Physicians: Evidence from a Cross-Sectional Analysis," Johns Hopkins Medical Journal, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 106)
  - 30 - "Primary Health Care, Past, Present, and Future", 1980 (Box 13, Folder 107)
  - 31 - "Regulation of Hospital Costs: The Evidence on Performance," Duke University Medical Center, 1981 February 5 (Box 13, Folder 108)
  - 32 - "Contracting with Community Health Centers," New Approaches to the Medicaid Crisis Forum, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 109)
  - 33 - "On Medicare and Medicaid in the U.S.," Symposium on Social Policy in a Free Market Economy, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 110)
  - 34 - "Computer Assisted Health Plan for the Elderly", 1982 November (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - 35 - "Public-Policy Implications", 1982 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - 36 - "Health Implications of Aging in America", 1983 February (Box 13, Folder 113-114)
  - 37 - "Uninsured and Underserved: Inequities in Health Care in the United States," MMFQ, Health and Society, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 115)
  - 38 - "Financing Health Care for the Elderly in the U.S." Current Policy Debate and Future Directions", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 116)
  - 39 - "Gaps in Insurance Coverage: Impact on Health Care in the United States," Hospital Practice Journal, 1983 June (Box 14, Folder 117)
  - 40 - "Comprehensive Employment Policy in the Health Sector," Congressional Research Service, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 118)
  - 41- "Health Policy: An Overview", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 119)
  - 42 - "The Crisis in Medicare," New York Times Economic Scene, 1983 August 24 (Box 14, Folder 120)
  - 43 - "The Upward Spiral of Health Care Costs" and "Health Care's Soaring Costs", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 121)
  - 43A - "The Upward Spiral of Health Care Costs" and "Health Care's Soaring Costs", 1983 (Box 14, Folder 122)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from research - contains personal information.
  - 44 - "Computer Assisted Planning: Application to Health of the Elderly by the Year 2000", 1984 (Box 14, Folder 123)
  - 45 - "The Impact of Physician Supply on Health Care Costs," Columbia University, 1982 June 3 (Box 15, Folder 124)
  - 46 - "Medicare Financing Reform: A New Medicare Premium," MMFQ Health and Society, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 125)
  - 47 - "Medicare Reconsidered", 1982 (Box 15, Folder 126)
  - 49 - "Cost Containment and Health Care in America", 1981 (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - 50 - 1984 Democratic Fact Book, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - 51 - "Health Policy in the U.S.: Alternative Roles for Government, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - 52 - "Diagnosis Related Group Prospective Payment: Implications for Health Care and Medical Technology," Health Policy, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 130)
  - 53 - "Health Care Policies and the Aged," Handbook on Aging, 1982 (Box 16, Folder 131)
  - 54 - "Access to Health Care Resources in the U.S.: Ethical Implications and Choices," First International Congress on Ethics in Medicine, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 132)
  - 55 - "Access to Health Care: A Matter of Fairness", Center for National Policy, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 133)
  - 56 - "Health and the Great Society: Revisited after Twenty Years, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 134)
  - 57 - "Access to Social-Health Care: Who Shall Decide What?", 1985 (Box 16, Folder 135)
    - "Access to Social-Health Care: Who Shall Decide What?", 2013:002:001
  - 58 - "Computer Assisted Planning and Aging in the U.S.", 1985 June 20 (Box 16, Folder 136)
  - 59 - "Financing Medical Care for the Aged Poor," Generations Journal, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 137-138)
  - 60 - "Health Indicators: A Comparison of European and U.S. Experience," National Institute on Aging, 1985 August 29 (Box 17, Folder 139)
  - 61 - "Is Cost Containment Working?," Health Affairs, 1985-1986 (Box 17, Folder 140)
  - 62 - "The Economic and Health Implications for Aging in the United States", 1984 (Box 17, Folder 141)
  - 63 - "Medicare Reform Options" and "Charts on the Uninsured and Employer Minimum Health Benefits", 1983-1988 (Box 17, Folder 142)
  - 64 - "Health Surveillance in Europe: An Indicator-Based Reporting System", 1984 (Box 17, Folder 143)
  - 65 - "Aging and the Health Care System: Economic and Structural Issues", 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 144-145)
  - 66 - "Using Research in Policy Formulation", 1985 (Box 18, Folder 146)
  - 67 - "Expanding the Medicaid Buy-In to Medicare for the Poor and Near-Poor Elderly", 1986 (Box 18, Folder 147)
  - 68 - "The Changing Health Marketplace: Making Life Better or Worse for Americans?", 1986 (Box 18, Folder 148)
  - 69 - "Financing Care for Patients with Alzheimer's Disease: Policy Options", 1986 (Box 18, Folder 149)
  - 70 - "Health Care for Black Americans: Trends in Financing and Delivery", 1986 (Box 19, Folder 150-151)
  - 71 - "Recurrent Health Cost Issues Related to Effectiveness and Equality: The U.S. Experience", 1987 May (Box 19, Folder 152)
  - 72 - "The U.S. Health Care System of the Future: A Long-Range Policy Proposal", 1987 (Box 19, Folder 153-154)
  - 73 - "Projecting the Need for Physicians in the New Environment", 1987 (Box 20, Folder 155-156)
  - 74 - "Medicare Physician Payment Reform: Considerations and Options", 1987 April (Box 20, Folder 157)
  - 75 - "Research and Policy Formulation," Health Policy, 1987 April (Box 20, Folder 158)
  - 76 - "Medicare Financing and Beneficiary Income," Inquiry Journal, 1987 (Box 20, Folder 159-160)
  - 77 - "Reducing Medicare Payments for Overvalued Physician Services," HealthWeek Editorial, 1987 July (Box 21, Folder 161)
  - 78 - "Women in Health: Trends in Health Status and Access to Health Care", 1988 (Box 21, Folder 162)
  - 79 - "Access to Health Care in an Era of Economic Restraint: The U.S. Experience", 1987 August 24 (Box 21, Folder 163)
  - 80 - "Future Demands in Health Care for an Aging Population", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 164)
  - 81 - "The Organization and Financing of Alcohol and Drug Abuse Services", 1987 (Box 21, Folder 165)
  - 82 - "Health Care for Black Americans: The Public Sector Role," Milbank Quarterly, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 166)
  - 83 - "The 1988 Health Legislative Agenda," HealthWeek, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 167)
  - 84 - "Health Care Financing: New Directions in Provider Payment," Virginia Dept. of Health Continuing Medical Education Conference, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 168)
  - 85 - "The Greying of America: The Economics of Health Care for Older Adults", 1987 October (Box 22, Folder 169)
  - 86 - "Redistributing the Financial Burden of Indigent Health Care: Considerations for the Commonwealth of Virginia", 1987 (Box 22, Folder 170-172)
  - 88 - "Medicare Geographic Capitation: Implications for Beneficiaries", 1987 (Box 23, Folder 174)
  - 89 - "Frail Elderly People: Profiling the Problem", 1988 February 22 (Box 23, Folder 175)
  - 90 - "Uninsured in Virginia", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 176)
  - 91 - "The Internist: Health Policy in Practice", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 177)
  - 92 - "Price Controls for Medical Services", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 178)
  - 93 - "Health Maintenance Organizations in the United States: The Experience to Date", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 179)
  - 94 - "Health Care and the Nation's Economic and Social Agenda", 1988 (Box 23, Folder 180)
  - 95 - "Federal Physician Payment Review Commission: An Update", GBA Spring Meeting, 1988 March 16 (Box 23, Folder 181)
  - 96 - "Catastrophic Coverage under the Medicare Program", 1988 August (Box 23, Folder 182)
  - 97 - "Physician Payment Reform: Impact on Access to Health Care", 1988 June 28 (Box 23, Folder 183)
  - 98 - "Research on Health Care Insurance: Mismatch with Policy Needs", 1988 June 27 (Box 24, Folder 184)
  - 99 - "Reimbursement for Preventative Health Services: The U.S. Experience", 1989 May (Box 24, Folder 185)
  - 100 - "Focus on Vulnerable Population Groups: Children, the Old, and Physicians," HealthWeek, 1988 November (Box 24, Folder 186)
  - 101 - "Health Maintenance Organizations in the United States: The Experience to Date", 1989 May (Box 24, Folder 187)
  - 102 - "Old, Alone, and Poor: Policy Challenges Facing the New Administration", 1988 December (Box 24, Folder 188)
  - 103 - "National Health Insurance: A Proposal", 1988 December 30 (Box 24, Folder 189)
  - 104 - "Providing Universal and Affordable Health Care to the American People: Response to Robert E. Patricelli", 1989 January 9 (Box 24, Folder 190)
  - 105 - "Physician Payment Reform: Implications by Specialty", 1989 January 28 (Box 24, Folder 191)
  - 106 - "Paying for Preventive Care: Moving the Debate Forward," American Journal for Preventive Medicine, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 192-193)
  - 107 - "Reimbursement for Preventive Services: Can We Construct an Equitable System?," Journal of General Internal Medicine, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 194)
  - 108 - Medicare and Medicaid Encyclopedia, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 195)
  - 109 - "European Health Systems: Lessons for the U.S.," Health Care Financing Review, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 196)
  - 110 - "The Cultural Dimensions of Alcohol Policy Worldwide," Health Affairs, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 197)
  - 111 - "Improving the Performance of the U.S. Health Care System", 1989 (Box 25, Folder 198)
  - 112 - "Why Expenditure Targets Would Work", The Internist, 1989 September (Box 25, Folder 199)
  - 113 - "Options for Improving Payment for Preventive Care", 1989 September 24 (Box 25, Folder 200)
  - 114 - "Health in Aging America", 1989 October 18 (Box 25, Folder 201)
  - 115 - "Old and Poor: Policy Changes in the 1990s", 1989 November-1994 (Box 25, Folder 202)
  - 116 - "Settling the Nation's Health Care Agenda: Achieving Equity", 1989 April 13 (Box 26, Folder 203)
  - 117 - "Financing Health Care for the Poor," Health Services Research, Key to Health Policy, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 204)
  - 118 - "Health and Health Policy in the United States", 1990 (Box 26, Folder 205)
  - 119 - "Health Care Financing Reform: The Next Century," Resident and Staff Physician, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 206)
  - 120 - "Alone and Poor: The Plight of Elderly Women," Generations, 1990-2000 (Box 26, Folder 207)
  - 121 - "State Health Insurance Initiatives", 1990 February (Box 26, Folder 208-209)
  - 122 - "Health Financing in the 1990s," Community Responsive Practice: Values, Priorities, and Strategies, 1990 March (Box 27, Folder 210)